Guide to the Trent Collection of Whitmaniana, 1841-1992, bulk 1845-1849, 1854-1857, and 1864-1892
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1841-1944 and undated
  - Editions of Whitman's Writings Subseries, 1855-1944
    - The Sleepers. Illustrations by Marcel Gaillard. Paris: Hand press by Francois Bernouard, undated.
    - Song of the Broad-Axe. Philadelphia: The Centaur Press, 1924., Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
    - Song of the Open Road. Illustrations by Lewis C. Daniel, undated., Former call number: III-6B (Box III-6B)
      Uncut and unbound pressing of Daniel's edition, with an envelope of addenda.
    - Specimen Days and collect, first edition, first issue. Philadelphia: David McKay, 1882-1883., Former call number: II-1 (Box II-1)
    - Specimen Days and collect, first edition, second issue. Philadelphia: David McKay, 1882-1883.
    - Specimen Days and collect, first British edition, second issue. Glasgow: Wilson and McCormick, 1883.
    - There Was a Child Went Forth. Pictures by Zhenya Gay. New York and London: Harper and Brothers, 1943., Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
    - Thirty-One Letters of Walt Whitman, by Rollo G. Silver. Reprinted from American Literature, vol. VIII, no. 4, 1937 Jan., Former call number: Trent Pam Case
    - Two Prefaces. Introduction by Christopher Morley. Garden City, New York: Doubleday, Page and Company, 1926., Former call number: II-3 (Box II-3)
    - Two Rivulets. Camden, N.J.: [Walt Whitman], 1876., Former call number: I-3 (Box I-3)
    - The Uncollected Poetry and Prose of Walt Whitman. Edited by Emory Holloway. New York: Peter Smith, 1932. (2 vols), Former call number: II-3 (Box II-3)
    - Walt Whitman and the Civil War. Edited by Charles I. Glicksberg. Philadelphia: University of Pennsylvania Press, 1933., Former call number: II-4 (Box II-4)
    - Walt Whitman in Camden. Edited by and prefaced by Christopher Morley; photographs by Arnold Genthe. Camden, N.J.: The Haddon Craftsmen, 1938., Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
    - Walt Whitman, Poet of American Democracy: Selections from His Poetry and Prose. Edited by and introduction by Samuel Sillen. New York: International Publishers, 1944., Former call number: II-3 (Box II-3)
    - Walt Whitman: Representative Selections, with Introduction, Bibliography, and Notes. Edited by Floyd Stovall. American Writers Series. New York: American Book Company, 1934.
    - Walt Whitman's Diary in Canada. Edited by William Sloane Kennedy. Boston: Small, Maynard and Company, 1904., Former call number: II-4 (Box II-4)
    - Walt Whitman's Workshop. Edited by and introduction by Clifton Joseph Furness. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1928., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Whitman Interviews Himself, by Rollo G. Silver. Reprinted from American Literature, vol. X, no. 1, 1938 Mar., Former call number: V Trent Pam Case
    - A Whitman Manuscript from the Albert M. Bender Collection of Mills College. Oakland, Calif.: The Bibliophile Society of Mills College, 1939., Former call number: I-9 (Box I-9)
    - The Wound-Dresser. Edited by Richard Maurice Bucke. Boston: Small, Maynard and Company, 1898., (2 copies); Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
  - Bibliographies and Catalogues Subseries, 1922-1943
    Published bibliographies, lists, and descriptions of Whitman's work from the early years of Whitman scholarship and Whitman memorabilia collecting. Listed alphabetically by author or editor.
    - Allen, Gay Wilson. Walt Whitman Bibliography, 1918-1934. Boston, 1935. (Bulletin of Bibliography Pamphlets, No. 30)., Former call number: 1. Trent Pam 12mo A425T, 2. Trent Pam 12mo #7
    - Allen, Gay Wilson. Twenty-Five Years of Walt Whitman Bibliography, 1918-1942. Boston, 1943. (Bulletin of Bibliography Pamphlets, No. 30)., Former call number: Trent IV A425T
    - Hanaburgh, E. F., editor. Manuscripts, Autograph Letters, First Editions and Portraits of Walt Whitman. New York, 1936. (American Art Association. Anderson Galleries. Catalogue Number 4251)., Former call number: Trent IV B922 MA
    - Kern, Jerome. The Library of Jerome Kern. New York, 1929. (Anderson Galleries. Catalogue Numbers 2307 and 2311). (2 vols), Former call number: Trent IV K39 L
    - Landauer, Bella C. Leaves of Music by Walt Whitman. Privately printed at the Harbor Press, 1937, no. 18 of 60., Former call number: I-9A (Box I-9A)
    - Rare Books and Manuscripts Collected by the Late A. Edward Newton. New York, 1941. Brochure., Former call number: Trent IV N561 R
    - Rare Books, Original Drawings, Autograph Letters, and Manuscripts, Collected by the Late A. Edward Newton.. New York, 1941. (Parke-Bernet Galleries. Catalogue Numbers 276, 284, and 306). (3 vols)
    - Shay, Frank. The Bibliography of Walt Whitman. New York, 1920. No. 313 of 500., Former call number: Trent IV 12mo S538B
    - Sprague, Mrs. Frank Julian. A List of Manuscripts, Books, Portraits, Prints, Broadsides and Memorabilia in Commemoration of the One Hundred and Twentieth Anniversary of the Birth of Walt Whitman. Exhibited at the Library of Congress, 1939., (2 copies); Former call number: Pam S766 L
    - Tashjian, Nouvart, editor. Index to Early American Periodical Literature, 1728-1870. No. 3: Walt Whitman, 1819-1892. New York, 1941., Former call number: Pam T197 W
    - Wells, Carolyn, and Goldsmith, Alfred F. A Concise Bibliography of the Works of Walt Whitman, with a Supplement of Fifty Books about Whitman. Boston and New York, 1922. No. 495 of 550 copies., Former call number: Trent IV 12mo W453 C
- Clippings Series, 1845-1891 and undated (bulk 1845-1855)
  This series consists of two groups: large collections of clippings (listed first), and clippings of individual articles. The former are listed by the heading given each collection in Frey and the contents are described briefly. The latter are listed alphabetically by article title and are further identified by periodical or anthology and date.
  - [Magazine and Newspaper Clippings] (Frey's heading), (44 clippings); Former call number: II-7A 182 (Box II-7A 182)
    Articles on a broad range of subjects, dating 1845-1871, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - [Magazine Articles and Clippings] (Frey's heading), (17 clippings); Former call number: MS q 186 (Volume MS q 186)
    Subjects dating 1849-1860, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - [Newspaper and Magazine Items] (Frey's heading), (29 clippings); Former call number: MS q 188 (Volume MS q 188)
    Subjects dating 1845-1891, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - [Notes and Clippings, Chiefly on Eastern Poetry] (Frey's heading), (4 items); Former call number: MS 158 (Volume MS 158)
    Clippings with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - [On the Wreck of the San Francisco] (Frey's heading), (6 items); Former call number: II-7B or III-6B 189 (Box II-7B or III-6B 189)
    Clippings from New York Tribune, 1854 Jan.-Feb., on the wreck of the steamer San Francisco, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Anacreon, Former call number: MS 151 (Volume MS 151)
    pp. 236-42 from Thoreau's A Week on the Concord and Merrimack Rivers
  - Arnold's Lectures on Modern History, Former call number: MS 177 (Volume MS 177)
    From the United States Democratic Review, vol. XVII (Oct. 1845), pp. 247-56, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Chaucer, Former call number: MS 178 (Volume MS 178)
    From the North British Review, American edition, vol. X (Feb. 1849), pp. 157-78, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Christopher Under Canvass, Former call number: MS 179 (Volume MS 179)
    From Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine, vol. LXV (June 1849), pp. 763-6, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Early Roman History, Former call number: MS q 185 (Volume MS q 185)
    From Western Review, vol. I (Apr. 1846), pp. 211-74, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Egotism. As Manifested in the Works and Lives of Great and Small Men, Former call number: MS 180 (Volume MS 180)
    From Graham's Magazine, vol. XXVII (Mar. 1845), pp.97-103, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Excerpts and Strike and Tramp question, Former call number: II-7B 190 (Box II-7B 190)
    Autograph MS fragments (5 items) and newspaper clippings (48 items); the collection "deals with the tramp and strike problems in the United States" (Frey)
  - The French Moralists, Former call number: MS 152 (Volume MS 152)
    From American Whig Review, vol. II (Nov. 1845), pp. 497- 504, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Hymn of Callimachus, Miss Barrett's Poems, Former call number: MS 153 (Volume MS 153)
    From American Whig Review, vol. I (Jan. 1845), pp.35-48
  - Hymn of Heavenly Beauty, Former call number: MS 12mo 154 (Volume MS 12mo 154)
    From Half-Hours with the Best Authors, vol. 1, pp. 207-16, with autograph MS annotation by Whitman
  - John Bunyan, (2 items); Former call number: MS 12mo 155 (Volume MS 12mo 155)
    Clippings, the second from Half-Hours with the Best Authors, vol. I, pp. 527-34, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Literature of the Middle Ages, Former call number: MS 181 (Volume MS 181)
    From Westminster Review, American edition, vol. LI, (July 1849), pp. 181-92, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Modern Poetry and Poets, Former call number: MS 156 (Volume MS 156)
    From Edinburgh Review, American edition, vol. XC, (Oct. 1849), pp. 203-28
  - New English Poets, Former call number: MS 157 (Volume MS 157)
    From Putnam's Monthly, vol. VI (Sept. 1855), pp. 225-38, with autograph MS annotation by Whitman
  - One Thousand Historical Events, with the Dates, Former call number: MS q 187 (Volume MS q 187)
    From Memoria Technica, pp. 17-40, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Phrenology: A Socratic Dialogue, Former call number: MS 159 (Volume MS 159)
    From American Whig Review vol. III (Jan. 1846), pp. 31-46, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - The Poetry of Sacred and Legendary Art, Former call number: MS 160 (Volume MS 160)
    From Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine, vol. LXV (Feb. 1849), pp. 175- 190, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Political Poets: Waller and Marvell, Former call number: MS 161 (Volume MS 161)
    From American Whig Review, vol. III (May 1851), pp. 411- 418, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Pope, Former call number: MS 162 (Volume MS 162)
    From North British Review, MS 162 American edition, vol. IX (Aug. 1848), pp. 163-82, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - The Prelude, Former call number: MS 163 (Volume MS 163)
    From American Whig Review, N. S. vol. VII (May 1851), pp. 447-8; pp. 455-8
  - Progress: Its Law and Cause, Former call number: MS q 183 (Volume MS q 183)
    From Westminster Review, American edition, vol. LXVII (Apr. 1857), pp. 243-66; 277-88, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - The Prose Writers of America; New Poetry in New-England, (2 items); Former call number: MS 164 (Volume MS 164)
    Contiguous articles, from United States Democratic Review, vol. XX (May 1847), pp. 383-98, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Provencal and Scandinavian Poetry, Former call number: MS 165 (Volume MS 165)
    From Edinburgh Review, American edition, vol. LXXXVIII (July 1848), pp. 1-16 with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Recollections of Poets Laureate. Wordsworth: Tennyson, Former call number: MS 166 (Volume MS 166)
    From American Whig Review, N. S. vol. IX (June 1852), pp. 515-24, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - "R. M. Milnes' Life of Keats", Former call number: MS 167 (Volume MS 167)
    From North British Review, American edition, vol. X (Nov. 1848), pp. 39-52, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - The Romantic in Literature and Art, Former call number: MS q 184 (Volume MS q 184)
    From Sartain's Magazine, vol. V (Nov. 1849), pp. 297- 304, with autograph MS annotation by Whitman
  - Scottish Poetry...Robert Burns, Former call number: MS 168 (Volume MS 168)
    Two clippings from an unidentified anthology, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Shakespeare's Sonnets, Former call number: MS 169 (Volume MS 169)
    From Sartain's Magazine, vol. V (Sept. and Oct. 1849), pp. 153-8; pp. 217-24
  - The Standard Civilized Head, Former call number:
    From Life Illustrated N. S. vol. MS 159 II (July 5, 1856), p. 74
  - Taylor's Eve of the Conquest, Former call number:
    From Edinburgh Review, MS 170 American edition, vol. LXXXIX (Apr. 1849), pp. 183-96, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Tennyson's Poems, Former call number: MS 171 (Volume MS 171)
    From Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine, LXV (Apr. 1849), pp. 453-68, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Tennyson's Poems—The Princess, Former call number: MS 172 (Volume MS 172)
    From North British Review, American edition, vol. IX (May 1848), pp. 25-40, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Thoughts on Reading, Former call number: MS 173 (Volume MS 173)
    From American Whig Review, vol. I (May 1845), pp. 483-96, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Translators of Homer, Former call number: MS 174 (Volume MS 174)
    From American Whig Review, vol. IV (Oct. 1846), pp. 351-72, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - The Vanity and the Glory of Literature, Former call number: MS 175 (Volume MS 175)
    From Edinburgh Review, American edition, vol. LXXXIX (Apr. 1849), pp. 149-68, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
  - Voltaire, Former call number: MS 176 (Volume MS 176)
    From Life Illustrated, N. S. vol. II (May 10, 1856), p. 9, with autograph MS annotations by Whitman
- Material About or Relating to Whitman Series, 1842-1947 and undated (bulk post-1880)
  Contains the manuscript of Richard Maurice Bucke's biography of Whitman, manuscript versions of essays, lectures, and another book on Whitman's life and poetry, and some personal manuscript material of Whitman's, including copies of his will drawn up by Bucke. Also includes a number of significant scholarly books and articles published toward the end of Whitman's career and for more than fifty years following his death.
  - Richard Maurice Bucke's Biography of Whitman Subseries, ca. 1880-1883
    Consists of draft manuscript material by Bucke, William O'Connor, and Whitman that was later revised and used in Bucke's Walt Whitman. Also contains large portions of Bucke's revised manuscript.
    - Draft Manuscripts
      - Bucke, Richard Maurice - Autograph MS draft of Whitman biography (complete), approx. 415 pp., Former call number: II-6A, 138 (Box II-6A, 138)
      - O'Connor, William D - MS copy in a professional copyist's hand of O'Connor's The Good Gray Poet. Included with Bucke's draft, listed above., Former call number: II-6A, 138 (Box II-6A, 138)
      - Whitman, Walt - Autograph MS draft of passage appearing in revised form on p. 136 of Bucke's biography. One page., Former call number: MS q 139 (Volume MS q 139)
    - Revised Manuscripts
      - Introduction (Autograph MS by Whitman, outline of his life that informs Bucke's introduction, 6 pp.), Former call number: MS q 140 (Volume MS q 140)
      - Part I, Chapter 2: The Poet in 1880 (Copyist's hand, autograph revisions by Whitman. Complete copy of the chapter, 15 pp.), Former call number: II-6B, 141 (Box II-6B, 141)
      - Part I, Chapter 3: His Conversation (Copyist's hand, autograph revisions by Whitman. Partial copy of the chapter, 15 pp.), Former call number: II-6B, 142 (Box II-6B, 142)
      - Part I, Chapter 3: He several times spoke of President Lincoln (Autograph MS by Whitman, one page.), Former call number: II-6B, 142a (Box II-6B, 142a)
        Cf. Portraits of Others Subseries (Saunders 75).
      - Appendix to Part I (Chiefly copyist's hand, 143 pp. Includes W. D. O'Connor's introductory letter to The Good Gray Poet and portions of The Good Gray Poet with revisions by Walt Whitman.), Former call number: II-6B, 143 (Box II-6B, 143)
      - Part II, Chapter 1: History of Leaves of Grass (Chiefly copyist's hand, 28 pp. Also in the had of William S. Kennedy and Richard M. Bucks, with revisions by Walt Whitman.), Former call number: II-6B, 144 (Box II-6B, 144)
      - Part II, Chapter 3: Analysis of Poems, Continued (Autograph MS by Whitman, one page. Appearing in revised form in Bucke's biography, pp. 189-90.), Former call number: III-6B, 144a (Box III-6B, 144a)
  - Other Manuscripts About Whitman Subseries, 1872-1938 and undated
    Manuscript versions of drafts and notes on Whitman's career. Includes a typescript of Newton Arvin's book Whitman (1938). Listed alphabetically by author.
    - Anonymous
      - The College Farewell to Dr. Bucke and J. W. Wallace. MS report of a meeting of "The College," Bolton, Lancs., 24 Aug. 1891., Former call number: II-6B, 147 (Box II-6B, 147)
    - Allen, Gay Wilson
      - Walt Whitman Abroad. Printer's copy of TS of Allen's book, 1955, Former call number: III-7A (Box III-7A)
    - Arvin, Newton
      - Partial draft of Whitman, undated, Former call number: III8A
      - Whitman. TS of Arvin's book., Former call number: III-7B (Box III-7B)
        Cf. Books and Pamphlets About or Relating to Whitman Subseries for printed text.
    - Bucke, Richard Maurice
      - The Genesis of Walt Whitman. Autograph MS, 13 pp., one page typed., Former call number: II-6B, 145 (Box II-6B, 145)
      - Walt Whitman: Man and Poet. Autograph MS, 15 pp., Former call number: MS q 146 (Volume MS q 146)
      - Wills of Walt Whitman. Autograph copies by Bucke of Whitman's wills made in 1872, 1880, 1882, 7pp., Former call number: MS q 150 (Volume MS q 150)
    - Bucke, Richard Maurice, Elizabeth Keller, Daniel Longaker, and Alexander McAlister
      - Notes W. W. Last Sickness, 162 pp., Former call number: II-7A, 149 (Box II-7A, 149)
    - Fowler, L. N.
      - Phrenological Description of W. Whitman, Age 29 Occupation Printer, by L.N. Fowler, N. York July 16-1849.. Autograph MS, with the list and numbers describing Whitman's head in phrenological terms, 5 pp., Former call number: MS q 148 (Volume MS q 148)
    - Frey, Ellen
      - Manuscript of Catalogue of the Whitman Collection, sections I-III, Former call number: III-9A (Box III-9A)
      - Manuscript of Catalogue of the Whitman Collection, sections IV-V, Former call number: III-9B (Box III-9B)
      - Proofs of Catalogue of the Whitman Collection, undated
      - Mss about Walt Whitman--Descriptions, undated, Former call number: III-9C (Box III-9C)
      - Whitman's Annotations on Magazine Excerpts, Clippings, Etc., undated
  - Periodicals Containing Contributions About Whitman Subseries, 1868-1943 (bulk 1880-1895)
    Published articles on Whitman's life and poetry. Although most items in this subseries are scholarly, others contain personal recollections or informal essays about Whitman. Items are grouped alphabetically by the author's last name; they have not been further sorted within each letter grouping.
    - A-B, Former call number: AW1 (Box AW1)
    - B-C, Former call number: AW2 (Box AW2)
    - C, Former call number: AW3 (Box AW3)
    - D-F, Former call number: AW4 (Box AW4)
    - F-H, Former call number: AW5 (Box AW5)
    - H-J, Former call number: AW6 (Box AW6)
    - J-L, Former call number: AW7 (Box AW7)
    - L-M, Former call number: AW8 (Box AW8)
    - M-P, Former call number: AW9 (Box AW9)
    - P-S, Former call number: AW10 (Box AW10)
    - S, Former call number: Aw11 (Box Aw11)
    - T-W, Former call number: AW12 (Box AW12)
    - W, Former call number: AW13 (Box AW13)
    - Oversize periodicals, Former call number: 1 (Opaperfolder 1)
      - Once a Week (portrait of Whitman), 1889 Dec. 17
      - New York Citizen, 1867 Aug. 10
      - Post (Camden), 1889 June 1
      - Frank Leslie's Illustrated Weekly, 1892 Apr. 14
      - Illustrated American, 1890 Apr. 19
      - Scottish Art Review, 1889 April and June
      - William Speers: "Walt Whitman's Camden Days," Philadelphia Inquirer, 1970 Feb.
  - Books And Pamphlets About Or Relating To Whitman Subseries, 1842-1947 (bulk 1880-1930).
    Published scholarly books and shorter monographs on Whitman's life and poetry. Listed alphabetically by author.
    - Library exhibitions and events, 1945-1980, Former call number: AW13 (Box AW13)
    - Anon. The Obliviad: A Satire. New York and London, 1879., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Arvin, Newton. Whitman. New York, 1938., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Auslander, Joseph. Five American Immortals, Worcester (Mass.), 1940., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Bailey, John. Walt Whitman. English Men of Letters Series. London, 1926., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Barrus, Clara. Whitman and Burroughs, Comrades. Boston and New York, 1931., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Barton, William E. Abraham Lincoln and Walt Whitman. Indianapolis, 1928., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Bazalgette, Leon. Walt Whitman: L'Homme et son Oeuvre. Paris, 1908., Former call number: Trent IV
    - _________. Walt Whitman: The Man and His Work. Translated into English by Ellen FitzGerald. Garden City, N.Y., 1920.
    - Beerbohm, Max. The Poets' Corner. London, 1904., Former call number: I-7 (Box I-7)
    - Binns, Henry Bryan. A Life of Walt Whitman. London, 1905., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Bloor, Ella Reeve. We Are Many: An Autobiography. Introduction by Elizabeth Gurley Flynn New York, 1940., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Born, Helena. Whitman's Ideal Democracy and Other Writings. Edited by Helen Tufts. Boston, 1902., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Boughton, Willis. Walt Whitman. Reprinted from The Arena. vol. VI, 1882 Sept., pp. 471-80., Former call number: Trent Pam Case
    - Boyd, Ernest. Literary Blasphemies. New York and London, 1927., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Bucke, Richard Maurice, editor. Comic Consciousness: A Study in the Evolution of the Human Mind. Philadelphia, 1901., Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
    - _________. Man's Moral Nature: An Essay. New York and Toronto, 1879., Former call number: Trent IV
    - _________. Walt Whitman. Philadelphia, 1883.
    - _________. Walt Whitman, with English Critics on Walt Whitman. Edited by Edward Dowden. Glasgow, 1884.
    - Burroughs, John. Accepting the Universe. Boston and New York, 1920., Former call number: Trent IV
    - __________. The Heart of Burroughs's Journals. Edited by Clara Barrus. Boston and New York, 1928., Former call number: Trent IV
    - __________. Notes on Walt Whitman As Poet and Person. Second edition. New York, 1871., Former call number: Trent IV
    - __________. Whitman: A Study. Boston and New York, 1896., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Canby, Henry Seidel. Walt Whitman, an American: A Study in Biography. Boston, 1943., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Carpenter, Edward. Days with Walt Whitman. London, 1906., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Carpenter, George Rice. Walt Whitman. English Men of Letters Series. New York, 1909., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Cheney, John Vance. That Dome in Air: Thoughts on Poetry and the Poets. Chicago, 1895., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Clare, Maurice. A Day with Walt Whitman. Days with the Poets Series. New York, n. d., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Clarke, William. Walt Whitman. The Dilettante Library Series London and New York, 1892., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Cotterill, H. B., and T. W. Rolleston. Über Wordsworth und Walt Whitman. Dresden, 1883., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Coyne, James H. Richard Maurice Bucke: A Sketch. Reprinted from Transactions of the Royal Society of Canada, 1906. Toronto, 1906., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Deutsch, Babette. Walt Whitman: Builder for America. New York, 1941., Former call number: Trent IV
    - Donaldson, Thomas. Walt Whitman: The Man. New York, 1896., Former call number: Trent IV